So, I'm an artist.
إذا، أنا فنان.
I live in New York, and I've been working in advertising
أنا أعيش في نيويورك، ولقد كنت أعمل في مجال الإعلان
for -- ever since I left school,
ل -- حتى عندما غادرت الجامعة
so about seven, eight years now,
قبل حوالي 7 ، 8 سنوات ،
and it was draining.
وكان الوقت يتبدد .
I worked a lot of late nights. I worked a lot of weekends,
لقد عملت في كثير من الليالي. لقد عملت في كثير من عطل نهاية الأسبوع،
and I found myself never having time for all the projects
ووجدت أنني لا أجد أبدا الوقت لكل مشاريعي
that I wanted to work on on my own.
التي كنت أرغب في القيام بها بنفسي.
And one day I was at work and I saw a talk
في أحد الأيام كنت في العمل، وشاهدت محادثة
by Stefan Sagmeister on TED,
لستيفان ساغمايستر في TED،
and it was called "The power of time off,"
وكان يطلق عليها "أهمية الاجازة"
and he spoke about how every seven years,
وتحدث عن كيف أنه في كل سبع سنوات،
he takes a year off from work so he could
كان يأخذ إجازة من العمل لسنة حتى يتمكن من
do his own creative projects, and I was instantly inspired,
القيام بمشاريعه الإبداعية، ولقد ألهمني على الفور،
and I just said, "I have to do that. I have to take a year off.
وقلت "يجب أن أفعل ذلك. يجب أن آخذ إجازة لسنة.
I need to take time to travel and spend time with my family
أنا بحاجة إلى وقت للسفر وقضاء بعض الوقت مع عائلتي
and start my own creative ideas."
وأن ابدأ الأفكار الإبداعية الخاصة بي ".
So the first of those projects ended up being
لذا أول مشروع من هذه المشاريع أنتهى ب
something I called "One Second Every Day."
شيء أسميته "ثانية واحدة كل يوم."
Basically I'm recording one second of every day of my life
كنت أقوم بتسجيل ثانية واحدة لكل يوم من حياتي
for the rest of my life,
لبقية حياتي،
chronologically compiling these one-second
وتجميع هذه الثواني الواحدة حسب الترتيب الزمني
tiny slices of my life into one single continuous video
شرائح صغيرة من حياتي في فيديو مستمر واحد
until, you know, I can't record them anymore.
حتى، لم أستطع مواصلة تسجيلها
The purpose of this project is, one:
والغرض من هذا المشروع، واحد:
I hate not remembering things that I've done in the past.
أنا أكره عدم تذكر الأشياء التي قمت بها في الماضي.
There's all these things that I've done with my life
كل هذه الأشياء التي فعلت بحياتي
that I have no recollection of
التي لا أتذكرها
unless someone brings it up, and sometimes I think,
إلا أن قام شخص بحصرها، وأعتقد أن في بعض الأحيان،
"Oh yeah, that's something that I did."
"حسنا، هذا شيء فعلته."
And something that I realized early on in the project
وما أدركت في وقت مبكر في المشروع
was that if I wasn't doing anything interesting,
أنني لم أكن أقوم بأي شيء مثير للاهتمام،
I would probably forget to record the video.
ربما سأنسى أن أسجل الفيديو.
So the day -- the first time that I forgot, it really hurt me,
في ذلك اليوم--في المرة الأولى التي كنت قد نسيت فيها، شعرت حقيقة بالألم،
because it's something that I really wanted to --
لأنه شيء أردته حقاً
from the moment that I turned 30, I wanted
من هذه اللحظة التي بلغت فيها الثلاثين، أردت
to keep this project going until forever,
للحفاظ على هذا المشروع إلى الأبد،
and having missed that one second, I realized,
وكون غياب ثانية واحدة، أدركت،
it just kind of created this thing in my head
أنه مجرد نوع من خلق هذا الشيء في رأسي
where I never forgot ever again.
التي لم أنساها أبدا مجددا.
So if I live to see 80 years of age,
اذا لو عشت حتى 80 سنة من العمر،
I'm going to have a five-hour video
سيكون فيديو من خمس ساعات
that encapsulates 50 years of my life.
التي تلخص 50 عاماً من حياتي.
When I turn 40, I'll have a one-hour video
عندما أبلغ أربعين عاما، سيكون لدي فيديو من ساعة واحدة
that includes just my 30s.
ويشمل ذلك فقط ثلاثينيات عمري.
This has really
وهذا كان حقاً
invigorated me day-to-day, when I wake up,
شجعني يوميا، عند الاستيقاظ،
to try and do something interesting with my day.
للقيام بشيء مثير للاهتمام في يومي.
Now, one of the things that I have issues with is that,
الآن، أحد الأشياء التي أعاني منها هو
as the days and weeks and months go by,
كلما مرت الأيام والأسابيع والشهور،
time just seems to start blurring
الوقت يبدأ بالظهور بغير وضوح
and blending into each other
ممتزجا بعضا ببعض
and, you know, I hated that,
وكما تعلمون، كرهت ذلك،
and visualization is the way to trigger memory.
والتصوير هو الطريق لتحريك الذاكرة.
You know, this project for me is a way for me
وكما تعرفون، هذا المشروع بالنسبة لي وسيلة لي
to bridge that gap and remember everything that I've done.
لسد تلك الفجوة، وتذكر كل ما فعلته.
Even just this one second allows me to remember
حتى مجرد هذه الثانية الواحدة سمحت لي بأن أتذكر
everything else I did that one day.
كل شيء فعلته في ذلك اليوم.
It's difficult, sometimes, to pick that one second.
في بعض الأحيان، من الصعب أن تلتقط تلك الثانية الواحدة.
On a good day, I'll have maybe three or four seconds
في يوم جيد، لدي ربما ثلاث أو أربع ثوان
that I really want to choose,
التي أريد حقاً أن أختار،
but I'll just have to narrow it down to one,
ولكن توجب علي اقتصارها لثانية واحدة،
but even narrowing it down to that one allows me
ولكن اقتصارها في واحدة سمح لي
to remember the other three anyway.
بتذكر الثلاث ثواني الأخرى على كل حال.
It's also kind of a protest, a personal protest,
أنها أيضا نوع من الاحتجاج، احتجاج شخصي،
against the culture we have now where people
ضد الثقافة نحن نعيشها الآن حيث الناس
just are at concerts with their cell phones out
هم فقط في الحفلات مع الهواتف المحمولة الخاصة بهم
recording the whole concert, and they're disturbing you.
وتسجيل الحفل كله، إنهم يزعجونك.
They're not even enjoying the show.
هم حتى لا يستمتعون بالعرض.
They're watching the concert through their cell phone.
فهم يشاهدون الحفل من خلال هواتفهم المحمولة.
I hate that. I admittedly used to be that guy a little bit,
أنا أكره ذلك. أنا أعترف بأنني كنت ذلك الشخص من قبل،
back in the day, and I've decided that the best way
في السابق، لقد قررت أن أفضل طريقة
for me to still capture and keep a visual memory of my life
بالنسبة لي لا تزال التقاط والحفاظ على ذاكرة بصرية لحياتي
and not be that person, is to just record that one second
ولا أكون ذلك الشخص،الذي يقوم فقط بتسجيل الثواني الواحدة
that will allow me to trigger that memory of,
التي تسمح لي لاسترجاع تلك الذاكرة،
"Yeah, that concert was amazing. I really loved that concert."
"نعم، كان هذا حفل مذهلا. لقد أحببت حقيقة ذلك الحفل. "
And it just takes a quick, quick second.
ولقد استغرق مجرد ثانية سريعة.
I was on a three-month road trip this summer.
كنت في رحلة ثلاثة أشهر هذا الصيف.
It was something that I've been dreaming about doing my whole life,
لقد كان أمرا كنت أحلم بالقيام به طوال حياتي ،
just driving around the U.S. and Canada
مجرد القيادة في جميع أنحاء الولايات المتحدة وكندا
and just figuring out where to go the next day,
و مجرد معرفة أين تذهب في اليوم التالي،
and it was kind of outstanding.
لقد كان نوعا من الإثارة.
I actually ran out, I spent too much money on my road trip
لقد اكتفيت، لقد صرفت الكثير من المال خلال رحلتي
for the savings that I had to take my year off,
من مدخراتي التي أخذتها معي في إجازة السنة،
so I had to, I went to Seattle and I spent some time
لذا توجب علي ، الذهاب إلى سياتل وقضيت بعض الوقت
with friends working on a really neat project.
مع أصدقاء يعملون في مشروع متقن حقا.
One of the reasons that I took my year off was to spend more time with my family,
أحد الأسباب التي أخذت إجازتي من أجلها كان لقضاء المزيد من الوقت مع عائلتي،
and this really tragic thing happened where
وهذا الشيء المأساوي حقاً حدث فيها
my sister-in-law,
حماتي،
her intestine suddenly strangled one day,
امعائها انسدت فجاة في احد الأيام
and we took her to the emergency room,
وأخذناها إلى غرفة الطوارئ،
and she was, she was in really bad shape.
وقد كانت في حالة سيئة حقاً.
We almost lost her a couple of times,
كادت تموت عدة مرات،
and I was there with my brother every day.
وقد كنت هناك مع أخي في كل يوم.
It helped me realize something else during this project,
ذلك ساعدني على تحقيق شيء آخر من خلال هذا المشروع،
is that recording that one second on a really bad day
هو تسجيل هذا الثانية الواحدة في يوم سيئ حقا
is extremely difficult.
أمر بالغ الصعوبة.
It's not -- we tend to take our cameras out when we're doing awesome things.
أنها ليست--نحن نميل إلى أخذ الكاميرات معنا عندما نقوم بأشياء لطيفة.
Or we're, "Oh, yeah, this party, let me take a picture."
"أوه، نعم، هاته الحفلة، اسمحوا لي بالتقاط صورة."
But we rarely do that when we're having a bad day,
ولكن نحن نادراً ما تفعل ذلك عندما نواجه يوما سيئاً،
and something horrible is happening.
ويحدث شيء فظيع.
And I found that it's actually been very, very important
ولقد وجدت أنه كان فعلا مهم للغاية
to record even just that one second of a really bad moment.
التسجيل حتى مجرد تلك الثانية الواحدة من اللحظة السيئة .
It really helps you appreciate the good times.
أنها حقاً تساعدكم في تقدير الأوقات الجيدة.
It's not always a good day, so when you have a bad one,
اليوم ليس دائما جيد، لذلك عندما يكون لديك يوم سيء،
I think it's important to remember it,
وأعتقد أنه من المهم أن تذكره،
just as much as it is important to remember the [good] days.
بقدر ما هو مهم تذكر الأيام الجيدة.
Now one of the things that I do is I don't use any filters,
الآن واحدة من الأشياء التي أقوم بها أنني لا أستخدم أي من التغييرات،
I don't use anything to -- I try to capture the moment
أنا لا استعمل أي شيء ل-- أحاول إلتقاط اللحظة
as much as possible as the way that I saw it with my own eyes.
إلى أقصى حد ممكن بالوضعية التي تراها عيني.
I started a rule of first person perspective.
لقد بدأت من منظور الشخص الأول
Early on, I think I had a couple of videos where
في وقت مبكر، أعتقد أنه كان لي اثنان من أشرطة الفيديو التي
you would see me in it, but I realized that wasn't the way to go.
يمكنك رؤيتي فيها، ولكنني أدركت أنه ليست الوسيلة لمواصلة الدرب.
The way to really remember what I saw
الطريق إلى تذكر ما رأيت حقا
was to record it as I actually saw it.
كان تسجيله كما رأيته فعلا.
Now a couple of things that I have in my head about this project are,
الآن عدد من الأمور التي تدور في رأسي حول هذا المشروع،
wouldn't it be interesting if thousands of people were doing this?
ألن يكون مثيرا للاهتمام إذا كان الآلاف من الناس يقومون بذلك؟
I turned 31 last week, which is there.
بلغت 31 من عمري الأسبوع الماضي، حيث.
I think it would be interesting to see
أعتقد أنه سيكون من المثير للاهتمام أن نرى
what everyone did with a project like this.
ما فعله كل واحد مع مشروع مثل هذا.
I think everyone would have a different interpretation of it.
أعتقد أن الجميع سيكون له تفسير مختلف لذلك.
I think everyone would benefit from just having that one second to remember every day.
أعتقد أن الجميع سيستفيد من مجرد وجود هذا الثانية الواحدة لتذكر كل يوم.
Personally, I'm tired of forgetting,
شخصيا، سئمت من النسيان،
and this is a really easy thing to do.
والقيام بهذا الأمر سهل للغاية.
I mean, we all have HD-capable cameras in our pockets right now --
يعني، أننا جميعا لدينا كاميرات قادرة على هذا في جيوبنا الآن-
most people in this room, I bet --
معظم الناس في هذه القاعة، أراهن على ذلك-
and it's something that's --
وهذا أمر -
I never want to forget another day that I've ever lived,
لا أريد أبدا أن أنسى يوم آخر أنني لم أعش من أي وقت مضى،
and this is my way of doing that,
وهذا هو طريقي للقيام بذلك،
and it'd be really interesting also to see,
وسيكون من المثير حقاً أيضا أن نرى،
if you could just type in on a website,
إذا كان يمكن أن تكتب فقط على موقع على شبكة الإنترنت،
"June 18, 2018,"
"18يونيو 2018،"
and you would just see a stream of people's lives
وسوف تشاهد فقط عرضا لحياة الناس
on that particular day from all over the world.
في ذلك اليوم الخاص من جميع أنحاء العالم.
And I don't know, I think this project has a lot of possibilities,
أنا لا أعرف، أعتقد أن هذا المشروع لديه الكثير من الاحتمالات،
and I encourage you all to record just a small snippet of your life every day,
وأشجعكم تسجيل مجرد قصاصة صغيرة من حياتك كل يوم،
so you can never forget that that day, you lived.
بحيث لن يمكنك أبدا أن تنسى ذلك اليوم، الذي عشته.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)